♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next sunday, a.d. ♪
♪ There was a guy
named joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ but his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ so they shot him
into space ♪
♪ we'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
- ♪ the worst we can find ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
- ♪ and we'll monitor his mind ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ now keep in mind
joel can't control ♪
- ♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
Let's go.
- Cambot.
- Pan left.
Hi, girl.
What a cool guy.
A wisecracker.
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
- ♪ and other science facts ♪
- ♪ la la la ♪
♪ then repeat to yourself
"it's just a show ♪
♪ "I should really
just relax ♪
♪ for... ♪
All right.
In through the mouth.
And out through the nose
or its equivalent.
Good, good, all right.
Now we loosen the lips
on a "p."
[All] Ppppppp.
Good, good, good, now,
let's loosen up that jaw.
After me, pumpernickel.
[All] Pumpernickel,
pumpernickel, pumpernickel.
Very good, and now,
for the epiglottis.
"The wire is wound
around the wheel."
[All]
The wire is wound
around the wheel.
Oh, hi, everybody.
Welcome to
the satellite of love.
Tom servo's just
teaching us the importance
and the proper exercise
to warm us up before
we go into the experiment.
Commercial sign
in 15 seconds.
No, no,
pronounce every word.
Make a nice, round "o"
with the lips.
Commercial "siiign."
- All right.
- Good, good, good.
We actually have
commercial sign, though.
Uh, joel,
commercial "siiign."
Commercial sign.
Commercial "siiign."
Don't push it, okay?
- Oh.
- Is it time
to touch pelvises?
We got commercial sign.
- I slit the sheet--
- [bots] The sheet I slit--
And five and six
and seven and good.
Okay, shake it loose,
everybody, shake it out.
- Very good.
- Hi, everybody.
Welcome to
the satellite of love again.
Uh, while tom and crow finish
their stretching exercises,
I'm going to enjoy
a delicious salad.
Well, you know what might
be nice at this point?
How about a nice backrub,
everybody, hmm?
Everybody rub
each other's back, hmm?
Uh, I have an idea.
- Oh, you do?
- Yeah.
Uh, let's do that
trust exercise you taught us.
- You know, where you
lean back and I catch you?
- Oh, say, great!
- Okay, me first,
okay, here we go.
- Okay? Okay.
Okay, now, when you feel it,
- just-- just trust.
- I'm feeling it,
I'm letting go.
- All right.
- I'm letting go.
- And so am I.
- [Tom servo screams]
Oh, you little--
toe monster!
Toe monster! Woo!
Oh. Well, anyway.
I thought I'd enjoy
a delicious salad.
The problem-- this is also
my invention exchange.
The problem with takeout
endless salad bars
is, once you leave
the endless salad bar
with your
take-out container,
it ceases to be
an endless salad bar
and starts being a salad bar
with really strict rules.
So I designed this special
take-out container.
It's got baffles
and air channels.
It'd take a scientist
to explain it,
and I'm from the humanities.
But all I know is,
when you take out the salad,
it's like there's really
a whole bunch
of salad in there.
Like that, see, whoops.
Spilled a little. There.
What do you think, sirs?
Oh, we think it's lovely.
Don't we, frank?
Yes, very.
Well, we have nothing
big and flashy
to show you this week.
You caught us in the middle
of our home activities.
Uh, frank, why don't you
show them that
birdcage thing
you're working on?
Now, here's something I think
you'll really like.
Now, everybody loves pets,
right?
I sure do, but the only problem
with pets is--
they're kind of unsanitary,
you know?
It's hard
to clean up after them.
So what I've done
is I've invented
this vacuum cleaner
for cleaning up birdcages.
We'll just
turn this on here.
Now, it cleans up newspapers
and birdseeds
and any... ooh!
Well, back to planet earth.
Your experiment
this week, joel,
is the first in the famous
gamera turtle movies.
It's a love story about
a giant turtle
and downtown tokyo.
Uh, frank, be a treas
and send that up, won't you?
[Frank chuckles]
- The bird--
- oh criminy, I'll do it.
I gotta do everything
around here.
[Alarm blares]
Oh, we got movie sign!
Wow, you guys
took kind of a spill.
We're okay.
Water, the source
of all life.
Our story starts here.
Hey, sandy frank,
isn't that when
you drop your hot dog
at the beach?
I-- huh?
- A "daieeeee" motion picture.
- Aah!
Blub blub
blub blub blub blub.
[Joel washes face]
Refreshing.
- Camera!
- Uh, it's gamera.
- Oh.
- Um, m-c-m-l-x-v
"daieeeee"
international films.
MR. McPICKLE WHIPS.
Hidemasa nagata,
that's japanese for
"in-a-gadda-da-vida."
Oh, I see th-- huh?
Or "I got into the gouda."
Planning, you know,
I'd like to be an actor,
but I really wanna plan.
- Plan.
- I'm starting to get
cinema-sick here.
♪ Fumi takahashi
mr. Kobashi! ♪
- [Crow giggles]
- That's dumb.
♪ Noriaki yuasa
mr. Babushka! ♪
Yeah, okay, okay, yeah.
That's cute.
That's cute...
Titles by
the atlantic ocean.
The indian ocean, whatever.
Special effects.
He must be the guy
churning the water over there.
Yeah.
Running the agitator.
Agitating man.
♪ Tatsuji nakahuji ♪
- ♪ mr. B. B. Rabudzi ♪
- now you're getting it.
Guys, that's
really annoying.
- Sorry.
- Oh.
You know, they could
tell us anything,
- and we'd believe it.
- Yeah, we have to.
We're at their mercy,
basically.
[Tom servo hums]
[Crow hums along]
♪ Utaro hojo risin' ♪
June hamlin.
Oh, death from on high.
Hey, guys.
The raytheon corporation
welcomes you.
Micro machines
at 12 o'clock!
And g.i. joe is there!
Mercy. [Growls]
Woof.
- There goes
the neighborhood.
- Here we are.
It looks wild.
- You can say that again.
- [All] It looks wild.
Let's start unloading
the equipment.
Anthony quinn?
- We won't need
everything at once.
- Little richard?
Ruff.
Arf.
Hello, how do you do, sir?
- Oh, I make a good living.
- We are from
the exploration ship,
jidori maru.
I know, I know.
Look, look, up there!
What do you see, squeaky?
Death from on high again.
Hey boys.
[Man gasps]
The devil's birds!
- It's just a plane.
- The engines are silent
because they're avoiding
the fighter planes.
I wonder whose they are.
Oh, it's the nelson boys.
- Their parents
buy them everything.
- The war even comes
to this eskimo village.
Soon there won't
be any peace anywhere.
- Hmm.
- Too bad.
Red ball hits.
Hey, toy boat, toy boat.
[All] Toy boat,
toy boat, toy boat.
Unique new york.
- Captain.
- Yes?
- [Joel] Yes?
- The ice is getting thicker.
- Oh captain, my captain.
- Should we keep going?
- Of course.
We must get through.
- Huh.
Do you think dr. Hidaka will
learn anything from the eskimos?
- Oh, get real.
- I certainly hope he does.
Yes.
Hey, look out, there's a patch
of water out there!
Huh.
- Huh?
- Captain!
Look, what is that?
It's death from on high,
I told you.
[Morse key beeps]
Um, if... you're not...
Wearing... any underwear...
Uh, smile.
If you're not...
Wearing... any...
Uh, they pulled the underwear
gag on us, sir.
Unidentified aircraft, sir.
Americans, what're they
doing in the film?
Have you spotted anything
on your radar screen?
No, sir.
It must be coated with
anti... electric
wave paint, sir.
- Cut! Cut!
Let's do that again.
- Okay.
Operator, hand me the mike.
- Yes, sir.
- Hey, it's curly joe
as the general.
Calling all planes,
fighter planes,
based in the arctic ocean.
- Hey moe!
- This is your commander
calling.
Over.
This is the strategic fire,
over.
- There is an unidentified
aircraft
he sounds like buddy hackett.
Eight-four-point-
two-seven-three --
look, he's got
frankenberry hands.
- ...latitude.
- Frankenberry.
At one-seven-six-point-
five-eight degrees.
East longitude.
- Uh, general,
you're drunk, aren't you?
- Intercept,
and escort it to the base.
If it resists,
shoot it down.
Roger.
Captain, will they
attack us?
Mm... I doubt it.
They're models.
Ground control
to major wong.
- Tally-ho!
- Tally-ho, you little vixens.
Answer.
What is your nationality
and flight purpose?
Phrase it in the form
of a question.
If you don't answer,
we will take you
to the american airbase.
He asked me! He asked me!
Break off. Give chase.
He gives good chase.
Answer immediately!
What is your nationality
and flight purpose?
Are you known for your
work in the theater?
Uh, you lost your muffler.
All planes,
prepare for action.
Fire!
Just a couple missiles,
that's all.
And that's just a warning.
Uh, break-niner, we got
mrs. O'leary's cow
coming on into runway three.
[All] Ooh.
[All] Ahh.
Pretty.
Ground show.
It looks like that airplane
carried atomic weapons.
- Yeah, yeah,
I think you're right.
- Which means we're all dead.
Did you see the force of that
explosion as it hit the ground?
- What a great story.
- Mercy. [Joel growls]
Be careful, though,
don't go into that area.
There's radiation there.
And, as everybody knows,
it can only affect you
if you touch it.
- Aah.
- Oh!
Jeez, I hate the sound
of squeaky styrofoam.
Yeah, when you slice it
with a bread knife?
Oh.
And so,
in fear and hot water,
the first slurpee is born.
Somebody's got
a toro snowblower down there.
- Check it out.
- That's neat.
Good morning.
- [Gamera roars]
- Now why can't I have
a cute shape like that?
Keep working on it.
All right,
quit throwing stuff at me.
That's good, that's enough.
Thank you,
I'm here all week.
Thank you, enjoy the--
calling fighter planes,
answer.
Calling fighter planes,
Hey, moe! Woop woo-woo-woo,
woop woo-woo-woo.
Impossible to make
contact, sir.
I'm here, uncle dave.
- Keep trying.
- Yes, sir.
Sir, I think somebody
is sending out
radio-jamming waves.
What are you doing about it?
- Find out where
it's coming from.
- Yes, sir.
Yes, sir.
Is the radio working?
Can you contact the ship?
I've been trying,
but the atmospheric conditions
are bad, and I can't
make contact.
And this little kid keeps
twisting all the dials.
What'll we do?
All right, dan, let's go back.
- Right.
- Yes.
- GOODBYE, CHIEF.
- GOODBYE, McCLOUD.
Thank you.
- Bye.
- ...Davey.
I'll see you in hell.
Hmm.
Or not.
Here, have some
maggoty meat.
Mr. Hidaka?
Yes?
This is the legendary stone.
- You passed that stone?
- Handed down from
our fathers.
Looks like a medium-rare
porterhouse.
Then is this the turtle that
lived on the arctic continent?
- I just told you that.
- Yes.
It is...
The devil's envoy.
- Kissinger?
- Gamera!
- Oh.
Kids go running for
the rich taste of gamera.
Gamera? Then my theory
was right after all.
Steak keeps.
But you see that
wave-like pattern?
It doesn't match
the other carbon.
- Oh, just trim that away.
Add that to the soup.
- Excuse me, chief.
- Where is it from?
- I don't know.
I know...
It brings evil.
We may have hit upon
something very important.
- Refrigeration.
- Could it be a creature
that's not known?
It's hard to say.
There are waves around it.
- It must be aquatic.
- Like a duck, sir?
Do you think
that it could be
a prehistoric creature
or from another planet?
Anything's possible.
When you dream.
Beef. Real food
for real people.
What do you think
it is, captain?
Uh, a couple of eskimos
looking at a steak.
I've never seen anything
like it. Very strange.
It looks like it's
a kind of a sea creature.
And you look like
a who from whoville.
Morning. Like my snow fort?
Gentlemen, you seem
a little tense.
Let me break the ice.
[Crow laughs]
- Break the...
- [Servo chuckles]
[Gamera roars]
- Uh-oh.
- Abandon ship,
abandon ship!
Oh yeah,
abandon ship to where?
--Abandon ship!
Abandon ship immediately!
[All] Abandon toy!
Abandon toy!
Hey, there's ernie douglas
as sparks, check it out.
They're abandoning ship!
And he's in pain.
If I had a wisdom tooth
like that,
- I'd be in pain too.
- The wheel, the wheel!
I've invented the wheel!
Everybody off,
I said everybody off!
- Let's go, let's go!
- That's my wheel.
Emergency, s.O.S! S.O.S!
Emer-gency, emer-gency.
Out of the frying pan,
into the icebox.
Echo.
Look at those little guys
down there.
- Ooh!
- How about a little
fire, scarecrow?
- [Crow coughs]
- Commander!
Uh, I mean, dad?
Last message from
the jidori maru.
Uh, would you sign this,
'cause...
- So I can go on
a field trip and stuff?
- Huge turtle.
- Don't read it.
- 60 meters.
- It's okay.
What's going on around here?
I don't know, sir.
Looks like a huge turtle
made its appearance.
A giant turtle would be good
as fudgie the whale.
- Enjoy carvel ice cream!
- ...Find out what's going on.
Ice station titan.
Hey, it's a ragtag
band of misfits!
I can't see a damn thing.
I don't know what's going on
here, it's pitch-black in here.
Oh, oh, that's better.
I found the spot where
the research ship went down.
But can't see either the crew
or the giant turtle.
Uh, looks like
they're flying over
the plothole for the film.
- Oh, there it is.
- That's big enough.
Unique new york.
[All] Unique new york,
unique new york.
Ooh, new york "news stud."
- Hello, ladies.
- Good afternoon.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have special news
and an extra guest,
dr. Hidaka.
Neil sedaka?
- Good afternoon.
- Thank you, doctor.
- Thank you.
- Good afternoon.
- Yoko.
- Please sit down.
- Thank you.
- Lookin' fine.
Ladies and gentlemen,
dr. Hidaka,
a japanese zoologist,
will now comment
on the great turtle
which made his appearance
in the arctic ocean recently.
- And then I'm going all coy.
- Dr. Hidaka, please.
- [All feign japanese]
- Ladies and gentlemen--
herro, welcome to regis
and kathie ree!
A very great continent
in the northern arctic region.
An extraordinary creature
lived there, whose name was--
- todd.
- Gamera. A giant turtle.
A monster of another age.
- Sweet.
- And this is
a legendary stone
handed down by the eskimos.
This gamera is--
- now, we prepared this steak
- before the show.
- ...For thousands of years,
imprisoned under an iceberg.
- However--
- sleep! Sleep!
He revived after
the iceberg exploded.
As the result of a...
Of an atomic bomb.
Hmm, looks like kathie's
medication seems to be working.
...research ship we were using,
killing every one of the crew.
We three were
not on board then.
- And so my daughter and i--
- uh, over here.
...were spared,
and also a young reporter.
Oh, you mean "news stud."
I warn all of you
that gamera is violent
and must therefore
be approached
the utmost caution.
- But also, gamera--
- he's on the wrong camera.
- ...is expected to die shortly
due to radioactivity.
- Psst! Psst!
And so, I say--
- I pray that
this will happen soon--
- [bots whisper]
For the peace
of the entire world.
- So send
your dollars to care.
- And that the monster will
vanish once and for all
in the depths of the sea.
Amen. The end.
Only, as a zoologist,
I greatly regret the loss
of a creature originating
in the dawn of time.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Aah!
- Hey, variety!
Smash! Crash! Turbo-bash!
Zack normany is sammy
in chief zabu!
The new york times
says god is dead,
and the war's begun,
and alvin tostig
has a son today.
No comics.
- What's this?
- [Man hums]
Oh, this is the universal
unsuspecting drunkard
about to have a brush
with the supernatural.
My legs are old.
My teeth are gray.
My arms are gnarled.
Foster brooks-san.
Huh?
Uh?
Oh, that old thing.
Oh! Ball of fire!
Oh, andy, it's a ball of fire.
Tell aunt...
Oh, it's one of those pesky
little flying pies.
I think that's
what it is, yes.
That's very strange.
I never saw
a ball of fire before
that changed its course!
I've never seen
a ball of fire!
Maybe it's the flying saucer
that I heard them talk about
so much lately.
- [All applaud] Bravo, bravo.
- We have a special
news bulletin tonight.
Flying saucers
have been sighted
in various parts
of the world.
Over london, new york,
and cape town.
Even an old farmer outside
of tokyo claims he saw one.
And he's old,
goofy, and drunk.
Would you care for a magazine
or a newspaper, sir?
- I'll take anything from you.
- Oh, thank you very much.
The captain has turned off
the no-dubbing sign.
You are free to speak
any language you choose.
Flying saucers are
the sole topic of conversation.
Gamera has lost
his popularity.
Oh, they put him
in a bad time-slot,
- following "sunday best."
- Gamera was hit by radiation.
- Ooh, what a killer.
- Maybe he's dead by now.
Anyhow, I wish he had
been done away with
for good and for
the peace of the world.
- Ow-- wake up!
- You really mean
everyone on the jidori maru
was killed?
And that the three of us
are the only survivors?
Yes, my dear.
It happened when we were
at the eskimo village,
studying the ancient carvings
on that stone.
Doctor, there's something
that I wanted to tell you.
- There's no smoking
on this flight.
- Before we started out
for the eskimo village,
while we were still onboard,
the photographers
and reporters
drew lots for
this assignment.
- To see who would
accompany you.
- Lots and lots.
And you're the lucky man
who won the draw, right?
Lucky, indeed.
There were at least
seven or eight
cameramen along with us.
- Now they're gamera-men.
- They were not so lucky.
- Gamera.
- All of them perished
in the arctic ocean.
- All of them except
peter arnett.
- Yes.
It was a lottery
with human lives.
Written by shirley jackson.
Excuse me.
One of those photographers
made me an offer.
We were to be married
in may.
- A bottle of whiskey
to exchange places.
- Oh.
But I didn't accept it.
I guess running around
on the ice
sounded a lot more
interesting
than staying onboard, right?
- Yes, that's partly it.
- That's a cheap shot.
Only, I had
something else in mind.
- Catherine--
- whoa.
The real reason is that
I wanted to be with you.
- What?
- Oh, would you lay off her?
...lucky charm
of the expedition.
Catherine, I'll always consider
that you saved my life.
But... you can't.
- Yes, yes!
- Oh, a magician!
...I'll always feel that way,
you brought me luck.
And you brought me
a porterhouse.
Meanwhile, on cape cod.
Pepperidge farm remembers.
- Hello
- [all] Hi.
- Nice to see you.
[All] Thank you.
I was actually
coming to see you.
Is that so? Has kenny
done anything wrong?
Not really, but he's done
a very strange drawing.
I thought you should see it.
Uh, that's me with
the arrows through my head.
- It looks like a turtle.
- Yes.
That's all he ever draws.
He repeats it every day.
A type of obsession.
- Kenny's not a bad student.
- He's just twisted.
Only he's very moody.
He even has a little turtle
that he carries everywhere.
Oh no, he brings it
to school with him?
Yes, he seems
to cling to it.
The other students
make fun of him.
They think
that he's strange.
Kids are perceptive
that way.
I realize that kenny's had
a difficult childhood.
Yes, he's all alone.
His mother died
when he was very young.
She was mauled by turtles.
...no more turtles,
at least not at school.
Yes, I'll talk to him.
- Don't worry.
- Bye.
Oh, and ask him to bathe.
We must have some rules.
Hmm, that little scoundrel.
Let me out!
Let me out! Please!
- I met kenny's teacher today.
- [All make barf sounds]
- Well, what did he say?
- That kenny was quite an expert
at drawing turtles.
When I was his age,
I used to draw girls.
Oh, daddy, you're so randy.
I'm finished eating.
Hmm.
Ah, now for some real food.
- Kenny?
- Uh-oh.
[All] Busted!
What are you doing
with that?
Evil things.
Horrible things.
Who's all this food for?
Sauron, the dark lord.
Daddy, kenny's taken
some food again.
- Hit him! Hit him now!
- Kenny.
I told you I didn't want that
pet in the house anymore.
It's making you
neglect your schoolwork.
- And girls.
- Come inside.
- I thought we were inside.
- Come on.
I know how much
you love your turtle.
But there are other things
in life just as important.
Like having friends.
You don't want
to live alone, do you?
- [Servo coughs]
- Set that turtle free.
Let him return
to his natural home.
It'd be better for you
to forget turtles.
Kenny, if you get rid
of the turtle,
daddy will get you
anything you want, all right?
- Hmm, it's a promise.
- Yes?
Tell me what
you'd like best of all.
Different parents.
What I'd like
best of all is...
What? Tell us.
To keep it.
[All] Wah waah waaaaah.
Timmy, it's for
your own good.
If you don't, I'll throw it away
when you're at school.
I'll swallow it whole
with beer.
And you know I'll do it.
You'd better
get used to the idea
and get rid of it.
Aww.
I know it's hard.
But it's really
all for the best, right?
And soon you won't
think of it.
We're getting you
a lobotomy.
You understand, huh?
Mm-hmm.
He cut your brake line.
[Servo makes flushing noise]
See you on the other side,
sweet friend.
All right, you're getting
in that toilet bowl.
Here's looking at you,
turtle.
So sad.
Goodbye, tibby.
Oh, tibby, it's--
I can't watch, this is too sad.
I never liked you,
you came in darkness
and brought only pain.
Let's go, I gotta go.
I'm so sad.
- I wanna see him
kill the turtle.
- Shh!
More fish flakes,
sweet friend?
♪ Oh, tibby, my tibby ♪
♪ my heart is a mess ♪
♪ I don't have
a protective shell ♪
♪ over my chest ♪
♪ so people can hurt me ♪
♪ with the cruel things
they do ♪
♪ yet somehow, sweet tibby ♪
♪ I know you hurt, too ♪
♪ oh, tibby, my tibby ♪
♪ reality's hard♪
♪ so tibby ♪
♪ let's play in the yard...♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Tibby oh tibby ♪
♪ he runs like the wind ♪
♪ a couple of inches ♪
♪ and then back again ♪
♪ oh-doh-doh ♪
Uh, may I take a verse?
Well, if you feel it, crow.
Oh, I do.
- [Crow clears throat]
- Well, crow,
then by all means.
Join me, won't you?
Five, six, seven, eight.
- Tippy--
- it's tibby! Tibby!
Oh, sorry.
Sorry, sorry.
♪ I love you
my fine little fella ♪
♪ even though you gave ♪
♪ the whole family
salmonella ♪
No! No!
It's not their fault!
It isn't their fault!
Crow, you take
everything good
and you rip my heart out!
- [Servo sobs]
- Jeez, I'm sorry.
Come on, crow, let him
finish his song.
Oh, okay.
- Go ahead, tom.
- It's just a stupid
old turtle.
Go ahead, tom.
Thank you, cambot.
♪ Tibby, my tibby ♪
♪ your blood may be cold ♪
♪ but I know that
your heart burns ♪
♪ as hot as a coal ♪
♪ it burns with the love ♪
♪ only turtles ♪
♪ can feel ♪
♪ tibby ♪
Is our love real?
My tibby, I'll never let
the dog nose around your bowl.
But you know that,
don't you?
I can see it in your
beady little eyes!
If you high-center
on your rock, tibby,
I'll be there
to help you down!
♪ The toilet's not
your fate, friend ♪
♪ you'll always
run free... ♪
♪ Tibby ♪
♪ long as you have ♪
♪ me... ♪
Do you realize a robot just
sang a love song to a turtle?
That was really good, tom.
[Servo sobs]
Thank you.
We got commercial sign.
- That was great, tom.
- Thank you.
[Servo sobs]
Tibby.
Psst!
Psst! Hey, kenny!
Who said that?
Who's calling my name?
That's not funny!
Huh?
What gives?
This is strange.
Howdy, howdy-- huh?
Oh.
Neat.
Those kids at school,
they tease you, kenny,
because they've never
tasted hell.
- Today we turn the tables!
- Kenny?
Know what I just saw?
Look!
Huh? Uh,
that's the ocean, kenny.
I don't see anything.
You're seeing things.
[Earth rumbles]
Oh, now you're
feeling things.
Kenny, stop it.
Kenny, nora!
- Quit shaking.
- What's going on?
Look, daddy!
What's all this about
not letting kenny
keep his turtle?
Gamera.
- Gamera!
Gamera! Get the camera!
[Servo chuckles]
Little play on words.
- Kenny!
- No, kenny's over there.
That's gamera.
[Gamera roars]
Oh, he wants to marry
a lighthouse keeper.
Aah!
Kenny!
- Hey, hey.
- [All] Jump! Jump! Jump!
- Jump! Jump!
- Jump!
N-- go, drop!
- Daddy!
- Jinx.
- Don't you crush me!
- Daddy!
Slip! Come on! Fall, slip!
Aah!
I will pet him and hug him
and squeeze him
and call him george.
- He all right?
- Aah.
Kenny! Kenny!
- Kenny--
- yeah, quick,
move his spine around,
he's had a bad fall.
Kenny!
Huh?
- [Gamera roars]
- Kenny!
I love you!
Hmm.
Kenny, kenny.
You're safe now.
Kenny, what is it?
I'm paralyzed
from the neck down!
Ah.
I was so scared.
Gamera saved me, didn't he?
- Yes.
- Sure he did.
- Gamera saved your life.
- Yeah, of course.
- You can keep him as a pet.
- Because he knows
I like turtles.
That's right, he's a nice
turtle, you little loon.
Gamera must have
a good heart.
Yes, gamera's a good turtle.
- Yeah, whatever.
- Yes, he is good.
He is good.
Yes, he is.
Ow, my spine!
Excuse me, dr. Hidaka.
I have this stabbing pain
in my back.
...tell us what your
next expedition is.
No, I don't know yet.
Will you be returning
to the arctic on another ship?
Dr. Hidaka is wanted
on the telephone.
Excuse me, I must
take that call.
I'm really happening
right now, pardon me.
- There you are, sir.
- Thank you.
Uh, kenny's been
badly wounded.
You may want
to know about it.
He's been really hurt.
- He really is.
- That's fantastic, yes,
I'll come right away.
Boy, I'm really surprised
that you--
it's incredible--
that was the university.
- Spielberg offered him $250.
- Gamera has just been sighted
- near hokkaido.
- [They gasp]
- Please arrange
for plane tickets.
- Yes.
Dr. Hidaka, may i--
I'll see you very shortly.
- Dr. Hidaka!
- But doctor, I love you!
More and more reports
are coming in
about the devastation
caused by gamera.
Thought some of these
come from unreliable sources.
- Like kenny?
- Gamera is said
to be seen everywhere.
More about gamera.
...does he disappear
in one area--
- is kenny sleeping?
- Yes, he was very tired.
- ... completely
opposite direction.
- Aww.
Sounds like charo music.
Kenny, although
considered chunky,
is quite agile.
[Servo hums along]
Oh, it's tibby's burial mound.
Shut up! That's not funny.
You there?
Oh, tibby.
Tibby?
Or not tibby.
It's not-- stop it.
Shut up.
- Tibby?
Tibby?
Squish! Oh, tibby.
That's not funny!
Joel, tell him to stop!
Tibby! Tibby!
What're you worried about?
Tibby's long-dead, tom.
- Tibby?
- I'm leaving, I can't...
This is terrible.
Come on back, come on.
- Will you stop
with the jokes?
- Yep.
Tibby?
♪ And tibby, I miss you ♪
How does he expect tibby
to signal him? Light a flare?
Jeez.
Tibby?
- Oh.
- Tibby, why are you hiding?
I don't have the money
I owe you, man.
Now listen, I'll be
back for you tomorrow.
Rule number two?
Never work with children.
Man, they've been
on that plane for 48 hours.
Luckily, the in-flight film
is berlin alexanderplatz.
- Hi!
- [All] Aah!
- Don't do that.
How did you get here?
It wasn't very friendly
of the two of you
- to give me the slip.
- And make me wear it.
Didn't they miss you
back at your office?
Nope, I'm supposed
to cover the gamera story.
My arm-band for the airport.
It clashes with my tie.
Catherine, you're
still my inspiration.
I'll follow you anywhere.
Anywhere!
I'll slap a restraining order
on you.
What's the latest on gamera?
- Still not found.
- Hmm.
We must find him soon,
or there'll be chaos
everywhere.
Let's see, there's, um,
chaos here, chaos there.
Uh... hmm.
He's right,
chaos everywhere.
- Fellas?
Check this out-- chaos.
- What's that noise?
- I don't know,
maybe an earth tremor.
Try to trace it.
And try to dress the same.
Gamera sighted.
Heading for the geothermal
power plant.
And he's with helen hayes.
Come in, come in!
Come in!
Gamera sighted! Come in!
Follow me.
To emergency stations!
Quick.
And let's remember to call
each other in the morning.
- We all wore
the same thing.
- Careful!
Don't get too close.
Hold it!
Now, hold it up
to the light.
- Fly's open.
- Thank you-- oh, darn.
- Hello.
- Hi, how you doing? Hi.
How do you do, commander?
- I'm doctor hidaka,
tokyo university.
- Oh, I do all right.
- Hello.
- And I'm his assistant.
- Who are you?
- Oh, I'm from
a tokyo newspaper.
I'm sorry, but reporters
are not allowed here.
- Excuse me, commander--
- but I'm a bad reporter.
But this gentleman
is a friend.
He was on the arctic
expedition with us,
and he knows a great deal
about gamera.
I'm sure you'll
find his presence
and collaboration
very useful.
Oh, I see, you can stay then.
You can start.
- Yes, sir.
- Ooh, may I?
Yesterday morning,
gamera destroyed
a lighthouse
near this seaport.
And right afterwards,
- it dived into the sea.
- Dove.
Then it was seen heading for
the geothermal power plant.
A geothermal power plant?
What is that?
Allow me to explain.
He who holds the pointer
gets to the top.
...and high temperature vapors
used to rise from below.
By drilling
through the volcano,
we trap steam at
1,000 degrees centigrade.
And generate electricity
with it.
You mean the steam
actually reaches
a thousand degrees
centigrade?
Mm, hotter than
the santa monica freeway,
buffalo drive.
...high intensity temperatures,
don't you think--
wrong again, pony-breath.
- ...destroy gamera?
- I'm not so sure
it's possible.
Gamera has survived
even after atomic radiation,
and a thousand degrees
wouldn't affect him.
Dr. Hidaka,
do you know of any
counter-measures
to destroy him?
No, not yet.
What's the station's
maximum capacity?
About 350,000 kilowatts.
Well-spoken, my faithful
indian companion.
There's just a chance
it might work.
Thanks, johnny.
Mm, welcome back
to our tea-time movie.
Ted bessell
and georgie jessel
in lance the wonder dog.
[Servo clears throat]
Stop. Please.
- Commander.
- You can be replaced
by leno, you know.
Commander here, what is it?
We're ready, standing by.
Roger.
Oh, just doing some
sight-seeing.
Everything's set.
We can attack now, doctor.
It's so bumpy.
Maybe we can do it
without a shot.
It'll be a lot better
for all.
You think we can?
[Alarm rings]
Quittin' time at the quarry!
Yabba-dabba-doo!
Sounds like flintstones,
you see.
- Mm-hmm. I got it.
- Okay.
Thought it was a stretch.
- Everything ready?
- Yes, sir.
Would you guys hurry up?
Here you are, sir.
- Thank you.
- It's approaching
the wires.
Throw the switches!
100,000 kilowatts!
Pump up the volume!
Throw the switches again.
This time, maximum power.
Hey, I did already. What?
Ooh.
The electrical shocks don't
seem to bother gamera at all.
Incredible.
Hmm, and I was counting
very heavily on them.
...stronger than before.
As if the electricity
gives it renewed energy.
Oh, shut up.
It charges it
like a battery.
- Commander?
- Yes, sir?
- I think you
should attack now.
- Yes, sir.
- I've gotta get a sandwich.
- Attack!
Yes, sir.
Fire all cannons!
Ooh!
Turtle storm.
Oops! I'm clumsy, sorry.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
Gamera,
steaming mad at dirt.
Three mile island.
The real story.
Oh, hah, I'm so...
Where are those keys?
[Crow chuckles]
Slow.
I can never
find shoes that fit.
- He's hard on shoes.
- Oh, that one.
- Yep.
- That one.
Big trouble.
Bullets bounce right off.
[Gamera roars]
Kenny!
Guy...
Kenny...
Doesn't he kind of look like
godzilla with a backpack on?
- Yeah.
- Just a little bit.
[Crow slurps]
Really makes you think,
don't it?
Commander, it looks
like we failed.
We must find
a stronger weapon.
I'll have to go back
to the university.
- You stay here.
- Yes, but--
- don't worry--
is that the orkin man
back there in the back?
...consult a colleague,
and in the meantime,
I want you to evacuate
everybody.
- Understand, commander?
- Yes, sir.
- Good, thank you.
Meanwhile, at jackie chan
technical college.
And that's how things done,
professor murase.
Hmm, so, extra crispy
or regular?
...legends did mention
fire-eating turtles.
But in the 20th century,
I must admit it's
very difficult to believe.
But it's true.
Gamera doesn't seem
to have any weakness.
Except for betting on dogs.
There is something I can say.
[Servo mumbles]
Gamera's body must be
stronger than metal.
And if that's true,
the situation
is even more serious
than we thought.
It has the power
to convert organic matter
- INTO INORGANIC MATTER.
- LIKE McDONALDS.
And that means
nuclear weapons
are totally useless
against it.
- Yes, that's it.
- Quite.
The energy produced
by nuclear explosions
only seems to revitalize it,
giving it unlimited
energy resources.
- Some jerky?
- Mm, pickled eggs.
...find some counter-force
that will neutralize it, right?
And as for the markings
on this stone here,
I'm not sure
they represent waves.
But the eskimo
said they were.
- Oh, what do they know?
- The eskimo was only
repeating old stories
and folk tales.
But perhaps these carvings
can unravel a great mystery.
The secret ingredient in k.C.
Masterpiece barbecue sauce.
It's roger ramjet
and his american eagles!
Kenny!
My darling kenny!
He's in pain, isn't he?
[All make slurping sounds]
Commander, I believe we ought
to call u.N. Headquarters.
Oh, so you're in charge now?
You're right.
Contact them immediately.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, right,
"good morning. Yeah, u.N.?
"This is joe
down at the base.
Can we use your
missiles? Not!"
- Good morning!
- Rise and shine.
Good morning, everybody.
Go, gamera!
Go away, gamera!
Oh, put a sock in it, kid!
He's fish-food.
No!
- I'm doctor murase.
- Sir.
- Have you all
your weapons--
- I'm the colonel.
Yes, sir. I guarantee
that gamera won't
escape us again.
- We have even requested extra
missiles from the u.s. forces.
- Uh-huh.
Commander, all the missiles
are in firing position.
Good, start firing.
- If you remember
the colonel, why cook?
Don't shoot gamera!
He's good, he's good!
Let's listen to what
kenny has to say.
Yes, it might be a mistake.
Maybe we shouldn't
use those missiles.
Why not? It's the only way
to kill that monster.
Because kenny said so.
Gamera is a creature
that feeds on fire.
Using missiles would
not do any good.
It would only cause
unnecessary destruction.
No, don't use missiles.
I see. Sergeant?
Call it off.
- Yes, sir.
- Huh.
- Just like that, huh?
- Sir, thanks a lot.
Gamera saved my life
for me, once.
Yeah, great.
Guards? Guards?
Gamera is a good turtle,
isn't he, sir?
Well, son, I just pray
that you're right.
Yep, what he's done today
has been a benefit
to all, kenny.
[Servo whistles]
- Hey, saturday
mystery movie!
- Commander?
- What is it?
- They put pepperoni
on your pizza.
The plant
is completely destroyed.
I told you
to water the plant!
- I see.
- You're fired.
You heard that, doctor.
Everything's destroyed.
There's nothing we can do
against such terrifying forces--
except have another drink.
Dr. Hidaka, is there
anything else we can try?
- Love. What about love?
- There is one thing
that has just
occurred to me.
- It's love.
- Nature works
in mysterious ways.
Gamera is a creature
that feeds on fire.
It withstands great heat
I wondered if it would
succumb to the opposite.
I mean very low
temperatures.
Temperatures below zero.
Something like
a deep-freeze treatment.
Carvel!
Most fresh ice cream
- at home.
- ...Haven't used yet.
- Cute.
- This is still
a military secret.
But the army has a bomb that
can freeze just about anything.
You mean, it can
really freeze anything?
- Yes.
- Even a man's passion?
It was only
developed recently.
They tried it
in the jungle to freeze
all sorts of animals
and plants.
I think it's the best chance
we've got left.
So I think we should try it.
- Do you agree?
- Yes.
- Mm, sure, why not?
- I see.
Do you really think
it might work?
It's worked
very well so far.
Mm-hmm. Colonel?
In that case,
we should use it
against gamera, commander.
- Yes.
- There is one thing.
- It's really pricey.
- It's only effective
for ten minutes.
Only ten minutes?
It's still experimental,
and after that,
things thaw quickly.
So we've only got ten minutes
in which to trap gamera.
So it's ten minutes, then.
What happens if gamera
revives beforehand?
- Freezer burn.
- I don't know.
It's a chance
we've got to take.
Then it's ten minutes.
Next week on sky king...
That guy moves
like george jefferson.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah.
Gamera has started moving.
And a-groovin'.
He be funky.
- He's shaking his groove thing.
- Gamera is moving.
[Equipment beeping]
Damn.
We mustn't lose any time.
Yes. You're right.
We've only ten minutes,
not another second.
Uh, is that ten minutes
starting now,
or when you were in the room?
Gamera has just started
to head toward devil's mountain.
Roger.
I just hope this plan's
going to work.
- There's a resort town below.
- We have to work quickly.
We're never gonna get
any reservations.
- Mm-mm.
- I'm coming, kenny.
Hi. How you doin'?
Cigars! It's a boy!
The freezer bombs
only last for ten minutes.
- And kids want more.
- We have to deactivate gamera
within that time.
- Is that clear?
- Uh-huh.
So be careful.
If we make a mistake,
the whole plan will fail.
No pressure, though.
Don't worry.
Who knows what'll happen then?
Remember, we've only
got one chance.
- Time to go, guys.
- Let's get outta here.
- Dr. Hidaka,
everything is ready.
- Good.
[Missile whistling]
[Laughter]
Yeah, boy, eat it.
I've been waiting to do this
the whole movie!
That's it, crow.
Do do that voodoo that you do
so well.
Watch me, servo.
Watch me dance!
- Shh!
- What are you guys doing?
Oh, we're just, uh, singing
a cole porter medley,
that's all.
- Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
- No, you're not.
You're unleashing a bunch
of negative energy on kenny
via my jim varney doll.
That's what you're doing.
Oh, I wouldn't exactly
call it "negative energy," joel.
- Uh, yeah.
We just hate him, that's all.
- Yeah.
How many times
have I told you guys?
In the face of all
these terrible movies
we gotta watch,
you gotta keep
a positive attitude.
- Have compassion.
- Oh, I guess so.
Gosh, davey.
I never thought of it that way.
- [Laughing]
- That's right, goliath.
Well, anyway,
now, what I want you to do
is visualize kenny
in a good light.
- Come on. Come on.
- Oh...
- Do the--
- ohm.
That's right. Come on.
Do the exercise. Okay.
- Ohm.
- Now bring kenny
into your heart.
- You see that little
japanese guy in there?
- Ohm.
He's waving back at you.
Okay.
- Now, remember the tommy james
and the shondells song--
- ohm.
- ..."crystal blue persuasion"?
- Ohm.
Peace and good brotherhood.
"Crystal blue persuasion."
- Now shoot that crystal blue--
- I hate him, I hate him!
[Overlapping shouting]
Okay. All right.
What is it that you hate
so much about kenny?
Oh, he's a child of privilege
and the whole world
revolves around him and stuff,
and he can walk into
a restricted maximum security
military situation,
and they treat him like an adult
just because he befriended
a stupid old turtle.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And he never gets into trouble
even though his friendship
with gamera is causing
the death of millions,
and he skips school
whenever he wants to,
and he never so much
as gets sent to his room.
Yeah, and he can walk
into any book with
his pony pal pokey too.
Uh, crow, I think
you're thinking of gumby.
- Oh.
- Well, what about his voice?
Have you ever heard anything
so annoying?
[High-pitched voice]
Yeah. What did you do
with my rocks?
Daddy! Daddy!
Gamera has a good heart.
Now, come on.
As you guys get older,
you'll realize that people
don't mean to be obnoxious,
it's just that they're all
screwed up inside.
Oh. In other words,
as the great french film
director john renoir said,
[french accent]
"Every man has his reasons."
- Exactly.
- Oh. Gee.
I'm starting to see
things differently.
Now when I visualize kenny,
I wanna go up to him
and give him a big
snuggly huggly.
- That's good.
- And then squeeze him--
- mm-hmm. Yeah.
- ...And squeeze him
and squeeze and squeeze
and squeeze...
All right. You got
a time-out coming, young man.
- Let's get outta here.
Come on. You're coming with--
- and squeeze...
- Hey.
- [Yells]
[Clears throat]
What do you,
the viewers at home, think?
- [Crow] You're not
my real father.
- Shh!
What's the deal with kenny?
Is he a confused,
precocious kid
who's fallen in
with the wrong species?
- I hate you.
- Is he a starry-eyed dreamer
looking for
his long-lost mother?
Is he a juvenile delinquent
who should have the book
thrown at him
before millions more
needlessly perish?
Send your thoughts to...
...care of mystery science
theater 3000,
post office box 5325,
hopkins, minnesota, 55343.
- Stop it!
- And while we're at it,
what's all this
about jim varney?
- I hate him too!
- And what about
scarecrow's brain?
- Aahh! [Shouts]
- And kim cattrall?
- [Alarm blares]
- [Clamoring]
- Well, I think you were
a little hard on him.
- Come on, crow. Come on.
[Roars]
Ooh.
Hey, kenny, help me.
I'm stuck.
- Come on in, crow.
- Come on. Sit down. I'm sorry.
- Can we be friends?
- Yeah.
- Hi. How you doing?
- What a pitch!
This is the scoop
of the century!
No. Carvel is the scoop
of the century.
World's freshest ice cream.
- Again with the carvel?
- Miss, tell us when to start.
- It's funny.
- Doctor, ten minutes,
beginning now.
- Oh. Now ten minutes.
- Start.
Start!
- They're in.
- Mm-hmm.
Ooh!
♪♪ [Humming]
Here at toho industries,
we're working to keep
your trust.
If we can't freeze gamera,
no one can.
♪♪ [Humming]
- Okay, he's doing charades,
I think.
- First word, uh--
- swimming?
- It looks like
he's gonna move again.
The freezing bombs
are nearly set.
They'll begin to go off soon.
- How many minutes?
- Eight more minutes.
- You mean out of ten?
- Oh, crap.
I'm high-centered.
Hey, kenny, help me.
Hmm.
- Precision.
- Hurry, commander.
All right.
Everyone clear out!
- Let's go!
Come on! Come on!
- Let's get outta here!
- Huh?
- Come on!
- Hey, drinks are on me!
Let's go! Whoo-hoo!
- Uh, I'm with him.
- How's it going?
There isn't much time left.
Less than ten minutes,
I suppose.
- Oh, you got a little,
uh-- echh!
- Yech!
What are they gonna do,
turn him into a kite?
[Chuckles]
Dr. Hidaka, we must hurry.
Don't worry.
We're ready to blast.
- So am I.
- You got ten minutes.
- Whoo!
- Oh! That surprised even me.
- Aw.
- Aw. Now, that's sad.
- [Roaring]
- Aw.
I don't like to see this.
Tell kenny I loved him.
- Good night, sweet prince.
- Look! It worked.
- Duh.
- Yes. It's on its back now.
Yes, but remember, commander,
turtles do not have
the ability to turn over
by themselves,
so if we're patient
and wait here a few minutes,
it's bound to die.
- [Soldiers cheering]
- That'll be fun.
Permission to frolic
granted, sir.
Dr. Hidaka,
your plan was successful.
Yes. And if gamera
dies on that spot,
we'll have a precious specimen.
- Its whole body.
- And soup for everybody.
I'm melting.
Oh, what a world, what a world.
Commander, look!
It's pulled in its head
and feet.
You see, doctor,
it doesn't fly anymore.
- [Laughter]
- [Crow laughs]
- I don't get that.
- I guess you had to be there.
- Yeah.
- Crow got it.
- No. I'm just being polite.
- Oh.
- Whoa!
- Hey, check it out.
It's the batmobile.
Atomic batteries to power.
Turbines to speed.
Roger.
Ready to move out.
- It's a battery... see.
- Yeah. Yeah.
[Muttering]
- Comic book.
- Ooh.
Light blooming ground flower
and get away.
If loud, report.
Oh, I saw that
on ed sullivan.
Light spinner.
It's a big old fondue pot.
Ooh.
It's almost like
a flying saucer.
- Mm-hmm.
- It is.
Uh, looks like a giant
turtle potpie to me, sir.
Don't worry, people.
Gamera's only a shell
of his former self.
- [Chuckles, mutters]
- Ew.
Sorry.
Ooh.
- Hey, I can't see.
- Come on.
Looks like it's back
to vo-tech for me, fellas.
Yep.
- Oh, boy. I've done it now.
- Catherine, have you got
the stone?
- Yes.
- [High-pitched voice]
Yes. I passed it last night.
[Crow gags]
- Smash it into my forehead,
will you?
- Sir, the mystery is solved.
The lines don't represent waves
but clouds.
They were trying to tell us
that gamera
was a flying creature.
A little too late here, doctor.
Smash! Newspaper
hits japanese in face!
Ooh, that stung.
Why, it's the same creature
that I saw.
Oh, then the flying object
you saw was gamera.
- Thank you, miss hathaway.
- Yes. Exactly.
Oh, as the old saying goes,
"we see terrible things
if we live too long."
- And get terrible parts.
- It's true.
- Oh!
- [Brakes screech]
- Are you hurt?
- No, I'm all right.
- [Driver] Out of the way!
- The driver is either
missing or...
Right. Sorry.
What are all these stones?
Why are you carrying them
around with you, kenny?
[High-pitched voice]
To hurt people.
Life hurts me so I hurt back.
I suppose this is another
foolishness of yours.
- I suppose now we're going
to be attacked by a giant rock.
- Now, kenny--
- it's gamera's new house.
- Huh?
- Right.
- Gamera's new house?
Yeah.
Tibby's from gamera's family.
- [Joel mutters]
- Whee, this kid really
stepped off the curb.
That's right.
Meanwhile, on trapper john...
♪♪ [Whistling]
Focus, please.
Clear the shot.
Come on. We're trying
to shoot a movie.
- [Woman] Gamera's been flying
all over the world.
- All over the world!
But as soon as it's sighted,
it manages to disappear
immediately.
It's a shame we can't find
exactly where it is now.
[Dr. Hidaka]
Yes. But let's be thankful
it hasn't attacked
any places yet.
- Yes.
- Whoa! That's quite a beak.
- What am I saying?
- [Knock on door]
- Yes?
- What could be worse than this?
- Hello.
- How do you do, catherine?
- How do you do, sir?
- [Dr. Hidaka] Kenny, this is
a pleasant surprise.
- Not!
- Yes, I told kenny that
when he was visiting tokyo,
he ought to come and see us.
- Oh, good idea.
- I didn't really mean that.
- However, it is sooner
than I expected.
- Yeah.
You see, doctor,
our town had a lighthouse,
and gamera destroyed it.
- Ah.
- And now it's been built again.
- Our house was destroyed, too,
and now they're building that.
- Oh, that's neat.
- How nice for you.
- So we decided
to come to tokyo--
- I gotta get back to work.
- ...To stay with an uncle
who lives here.
- Oh, so you're a tourist now.
- There's plenty to see
and lots of monuments
to visit.
Do you see that structure there?
That's tokyo tower.
- Doctor?
- Hmm?
- You're going to die, sir.
- Is gamera still in hiding?
Yes.
- But we're searching for him.
- He's doing some social work
on the side.
Gamera must
be terribly lonely.
- Kenny, he's a turtle.
Get a mitt and catch a clue!
- Gamera's really very kind.
Gamera loves all children.
- You know, kenny has
a vivid imagination.
- Aw.
- That's so sad.
- Didn't he save my life?
- He's so sad.
- Gamera must be very lonely
- ...and must need friends.
- [All mock crying]
- I'm sure he must be
very hungry too.
- [Mock sniffling]
- Tibby's little
and gamera's big.
- Mmm. That's so true.
Except they're both
in the same family. I know it.
- I know they are.
- That's right.
[High-pitched voice]
Gamera demands
your instant death.
Hey, look at his neck.
666.
And they're both good
and gentle.
Your passing will be painless,
doctor.
- She's gotta commit kenny.
- Yeah.
Hello, akiro.
You look very busy.
- Uh-huh. Sure. Yeah, right.
- I see you're still carrying
those heavy boxes around.
- [Giggles]
- Yeah, yeah. Whatever.
- Must be nice, huh?
- Any fresh fish today?
Fresh fish?
[Chuckles]
Nobody eats fresh fish,
just that can stuff,
and it weighs a ton,
believe me.
- That's beer.
- Come back. Give me my stone.
- Kenny!
- You were born of a jackal!
- I don't have your stones.
- Yes, you've got them.
- I saw you steal them.
- No, I didn't.
All right.
Give him back his stones.
- I threw them away.
- Then you'd better go
and get them,
if you know
what's good for you.
Give the little freak
his stones!
All right.
You heard what I said.
[Groans]
You see,
I threw them off the bridge,
into the river.
- Die, die, die!
- Into the river?
♪♪ [All imitating foreboding
latin chanting from the omen]
Kenny, I'll get you
other stones
just like those, all right?
- There aren't any like those.
- Ohh.
Kenny!
- He's crazy, crying over
a couple of stones.
- Mm-hmm.
- Shut up. Beat it.
- [Cracking sound]
- Aahh!
- My spine!
It's all right.
Thank you.
In a way, I'm glad
he threw the stones away.
Back to
gidget goes to japan.
- Are you all right?
- [Demonic voice] Go away!
[Demonic growling]
Now, don't act like that,
kenny.
- You're a big boy.
- [Growling continues]
Sulking like that
isn't gonna bring the stones
back again, you know.
And there's no easter bunny
either.
There are lots of other stones.
I'll go looking too.
All right, kenny?
We'll look together.
- [Growling, barking]
- Kenny?
[Imitating dog panting]
[Chuckles]
Scoundrel.
[High-pitched voice]
I am the dream warrior.
[Chuckles]
Good riddance.
Hmm.
- Where are they?
- Boston, I think.
There's no load of fish today.
We're going to have to
go into another business.
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah, you're right.
I tell you,
there's something wrong
with the water.
All those nuclear tests.
They're throwing the tides off.
It's those scientists.
In a few years,
they'll kill
every living creature.
They already drilled
a hole in my throat.
This afternoon,
a series of floods,
caused by a reversal
of tidal waves,
inundated tokyo,
devastating whole areas
of the city.
- Neat.
- It's estimated
that nearly 3,000
shops and houses
were destroyed.
We'll now show you
film sequences.
- THE PASSWORD
IS "KOOKYGOOGOOWA."
- ACCORDING TO THE COMMUNIQUé--
- focus, please. Focus.
- ...Of the meteorological
observatory,
the source of the flood
remains a complete mystery
as phenomena
of this kind--
- ♪ phenomena ♪
- ♪ ba dee ba-dee-bee ♪
- ♪ ba dee-bee-dee ♪
...are now investigating
the origin of the tide,
which has also brought about
a decrease of marine life
along the pacific coast.
Ah, this is pearl harbor.
How'd this get in here?
- Hey.
- Not even supposed to...
...serious threat
to the food supply.
- Snafu.
- Furthermore, there were
a number of collisions at sea
caused by an interruption
of communications
- as a result of--
- the andrea doria.
I knew her.
However, this is still
being studied.
Powder.
There's going to be
a special conference
later this evening
at the university.
During which,
dr. Hidaka will talk
- to high-ranking officers--
- and kenny.
Are you a mod or a rocker?
- Unfortunately--
- I'm a mocker.
...not yet certain what
caused these catastrophes.
Though various theories
have been presented
by our leading scientists.
However, if I may,
I should like to give you
my own personal opinion
of the events.
- Hoo-hah!
- It is my deepest conviction
that gamera is the true cause
of all these sudden disasters.
Hey, somebody froze
the old guy.
He may be hiding somewhere
along our coasts.
- Mr. Freeze.
- Or under this table.
...then gamera is
what is undoubtedly
disturbing the natural
sequence of tides.
Now, this could've
been the cause
of these recent floods.
But forget that now!
Let's roll to rio
with lainie kazan!
However, to investigate
the case more thoroughly,
we have invited
leading scientists...
[Murmured introductions]
- I am--
- pull my beard!
--Not encouraging.
Every method used so far
has not led to any
concrete result.
Gamera seems able
to resist attacks
by all offensive weapons
known to us.
Therefore,
I am forced to admit
there may be even greater
catastrophes ahead.
More gamera movies?
Professor murashe,
before coming here,
we attended a special meeting
at u.N. Headquarters.
- It was neat.
- And they have recommended
your using
a different strategy.
And what is that?
Well, they believe that you
ought to put plan z
into operation immediately.
- Bluh-blah!
- Using the facilities
you're building at oshima
in the mountains.
Well, that installation
is still in
the experimental stage yet.
Using it on gamera might
exhaust its resources.
Its main purpose
is to advance--
- gilligan!
- Skipper!
Gilligan!
Skipper!
And if we failed, it would
set our work back
- at least 20 years.
- Bummer.
Furthermore, the facilities
are not ours alone.
- It's a time-share.
- This is a joint venture
created with the help
of the united states
and the soviet union.
- Mm-hmm.
- And we would require
their permission.
Well, since you
own their countries,
I think you could
convince them.
Haneda control tower!
Please come in,
please come in!
Haneda control tower!
Haneda control tower,
please come in!
Why don't you answer?
Because you're so redundant.
Oh! Look out there.
In the sky!
Ooh, that big-screen tv
is cool.
- Well, they invented it.
- That's true.
The one and only.
Now what?
Neat!
Okay...
Holy trinitron!
[All] Ooh!
I'll just pull over here
and check my fluids.
And, uh, just find
a place to park--
ohp, a little
too close to the pump.
- Sorry, that was me.
- So much about kenny's theory
about him being
good-hearted.
- Gamera!
- Yeah.
Kenny and the ken-tones!
Gamera jamera!
♪ I've got a turtle that's
as big as a whale ♪
♪ and it's about
to set sail ♪
Whoo!
Do the hou-chou finish!
At least they're wearing
practical shoes.
What is this, are they in
footloose all of a sudden?
Gamera is coming, everyone--
no dancing, not allowed.
No dancing.
Everybody clear out!
Aww.
Hurry, you hear that?
It's gamera, hurry!
Hurry! Everybody run!
Don't you want to live?
Get moving!
Ah, cool it, will you?
Gamera doesn't scare us.
Go to bed, old man!
We're not afraid
of a turtle, are we?
- Come on! Music, music!
- Dumb old turtle.
Will you shut up?
- I said everybody out!
- Disco turtles.
Have all of you gone crazy?
Did someone say turtle?
Look, it's gamera!
Look!
Do the gamera!
Cool.
- All right,
great drum solo.
- Whoo!
[People scream]
Hey, he's really bringing
the house down, huh?
Yeah, rock that town
inside-out.
Ooh, gotta hurt.
Daeiii!
Ah, that one was easy.
I hardly touched it.
Oops, sorry, that was me.
Evacuate the city
immediately!
Everyone is to evacuate
You are ordered to evacuate
to the suburbs.
Live the good life
in the off-world colonies.
Well, there's a building
overturned on highway five.
You'll wanna take
an alternate route.
New tokyo?
I don't think so.
Anyone seen kenny?
Here's a hot new dance.
Okay, so if we get
an 18-piece bucket.
Oh, something splashy,
I don't know,
extra crispy-- huh?
The best-laid plans
of mice and men.
We'll have it catered.
Let's go.
Welp, he saw london.
He saw france.
- He saw rodan's underpants.
- [Crow laughs]
Oh, excuse me, just ignore--
my fault, I'm sorry,
just get this--
I wonder how many times
tokyo tower has gone down.
He just hates the memphis
design group, that's all.
Well, now that we have
all the grills going,
let's get ready
to sautee some people, huh?
What, are they in supercar?
[All] ♪ supercar! ♪
♪ Supercar ♪
Have you seen kenny?
Ooh.
Hot foot on the freeway.
Man, the insurance
must be really expensive.
Yeah.
Uh, I'd like
a single room, please.
Escape! Escape to wisconsin!
Crunchy on the outside.
Roast 'em, tenderize 'em,
down you go.
Oh, hey, don't
get so negative.
Evacuate the city at once!
Everybody is ordered
to leave the city at once!
- Kenny.
- [All] Aah!
- Hurry, we must
leave right away.
- Don't do that.
Hurry!
There's still so much work
to be done though, sister.
Kenny, did you hear
what I said?
[Servo growls]
Gamera, it's me, kenny.
Don't do anything bad.
I am your bride.
I hear you, kenny,
and I obey.
I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good.
Please lord, don't let me
be misunderstood.
Here at exxon, we take
the greatest precautions
for the preservation
of our fragile ecology.
Here's the exxon valdez
at port.
That's our plucky captain
after a couple of cocktails.
- N.y.p.d.
- Frank converse.
- Jack warden.
- Is that everything?
Well, we don't have
kenny's rocks.
Oh, did you see kenny?
No, not since yesterday.
[Sirens blare]
Oh, come on,
who's she kidding?
She's been wishing for this
since frame one.
Kenny!
Damian? Damian?
Have another
deviled egg, damian.
Aah, forget him.
- Prunes!
- Explain to me,
dr. Hidaka,
I think the z-plan
must be supervised
only by united nations
scientists.
- Mm.
- I realize that gamera
is very dangerous.
However, we must insist
on total control.
As for my government,
I assure you, doctor,
you have our utmost support.
- Oh, thank you, topol.
- Only such a dangerous plan--
jeez, he is hard
to work with.
- By the united nations.
- I understand, thank you.
And I appreciate
your help.
My country will
always be indebted.
Now get off my foot.
There's one thing--
we can't be ready
for another 24 hours.
And that's at the earliest.
The question is,
what action can be taken
against gamera
in the meantime?
- Audition!
- Well, you see,
as a zoologist,
I believe that
gamera's violent nature
stems mainly from a deficiency
in his energy supply.
- Crow?
- Right now,
gamera is at a coal-
processing plant
devouring flames,
its favorite food.
- Mm.
- He likes cajun, go figure.
--Eight hours,
and at that point,
gamera will be in a much
weaker condition.
I vote red dot.
In that case, to keep the risk
to an absolute minimum,
gamera should be
kept there for 24 hours.
That's right.
And to do that,
- good luck.
- ...We must bring petroleum.
And keep the fires burning
- until we are
totally ready with z-plan.
- [Servo hums]
Industry! Responding
to government's needs!
[Servo hums]
One shining steel rail.
Run from kenny!
[All scream]
[People clamor]
Why? Why?
This world was never meant
for one as beautiful as me.
Gamera, honey,
don't go out too far.
You just ate.
I bet it's like bathwater
out there too.
Whoa.
It's day over there
and night over there.
Every one of our storage tanks
will be wrecked.
I think your
helmet's too tight.
I understand. Okay.
[Joel as john wayne]
Come on, the war's
a-this-way, pilgrim.
All right!
Come ride the little train
that's going down
the tracks to hell.
[Crow laughs]
And-- and that's
the tanks I get?
- Oh, that's great.
- Ow! Ow!
- Hey.
- That was his arm.
I need that.
Ouch.
Ooh, that was the midnight
train to gamera.
♪ I'd rather live
in his world ♪
♪ then live
without him in mine ♪
Did it work?
This is gamera,
knock it off.
Okay, right away.
All right, another tank.
They need another 24 hours.
You'd better get going.
Move it!
They wanna send
another tank.
Are you ready?
All tanked up, sir!
Watch it.
Gamera?
Kenny! What took so long?
[Servo growls]
Huh, hey,
they're in sections,
so you can just take
as much as you want.
Take all you want,
but eat all you take.
Yeah.
Kenny as woody guthrie
in bound for gamera.
Look, there's a boy
there on the car.
Hey.
- You'll get killed!
- Huh?
Hey, that guy's
risking his life,
and he's not even
the star of the movie.
Gamera!
I hurt. I really hurt.
Kenny!
Whee! It's fun.
Gamera, I'm coming to be
in union with you!
Hey! Come here!
- Come here!
- Leave me alone!
Don't touch me! Infidel!
I don't wanna go!
I... shall make you pay!
Come back here!
I don't wanna get off!
- I'm a toys r us kid.
- Let go of me!
Aah!
[All applaud, whistle]
Kenny?
Come on.
All right.
- Come on.
[Servo mimics train]
- Put me down!
Wow, that blast
really shook him up.
He thinks he's a train now.
Yeah, I'd cure him,
but I need the ride.
Run, bud ryan!
Spanking machine on kenny.
You know, you nearly
got us both killed.
You'd better go home.
No, gamera's my friend.
He's good.
Yeah, I know, I know.
Here, put this on.
Hey kid, get a dog,
would you?
- [All laugh at kenny]
- [Soldiers laugh]
I'll say goodbye
to gamera for you.
You gonna cry?
- One-two-three
- [all] Cry!
- Gentlemen.
- Start your engines.
I have excellent news.
I am proud to announce
that z-plan
has been completed
and is at your disposal.
- So?
- The world's
latest technology
stands ready for your
struggle against gamera.
- That's really neat.
-The question is,
how can we lure gamera
to our new installation
located at oshima?
- Send him an invitation.
- I'm sure it's quite obvious
to everyone present
that we will
not be able
to carry out our plan
if we cannot
get gamera there.
Professor murase,
I have a suggestion.
- Okay.
- Dr. Hidaka,
please continue.
To make certain
gamera goes to oshima,
we must use special tactics.
- Or use this map.
- You see...
Oh, he is.
Right now, the whole city
of oshima--
- hey, who's talking?
- What's going on?
The city is off-limits
to civilians.
Not even the press
is allowed to enter the area.
Kenny, however, is free
to move about.
- Well, it's goodbye
for a while.
- Aww.
It's not fair.
We've always worked together.
Shutting me out isn't nice.
It's a pity they just
don't want reporters along.
But we'll come back soon.
Sure. Just the same,
I hate being separated
from my goddess.
- [Giggles]
- Well, goodbye.
I'll be stalking you
at night.
Murase is staying here.
If you want news of us,
- contact him
at the university.
- Right.
- Goodbye.
- See you soon.
Love me... love me!
Omaha beach.
June 5th, 1945.
McHALE!
Hey.
Looks like they're
setting up a wedding.
I hope the crab puffs
hold out.
- [Servo hums]
Okay, everybody
off the trucks.
- Like this?
- Move it! Move it!
Move it! Let's go, let's go!
- [Joel joins humming]
- Move it!
Four score and-- oh, sorry.
He's gonna get prune hands,
staying in the tub like that.
Has dr. Hidaka left
for oshima yet?
Yes. He was on
the very last flight.
I certainly hope gamera
goes to oshima soon.
Go to oshima.
Man, apartments in tokyo
are hard to find.
Yeah.
[Servo hums]
Don knotts, a giant turtle,
and a japanese stowaway
add up to kooky fun in--
come on, let's
get out of here.
Uh, can I get my arm--
oh, don't worry, crow,
we got a spare upstairs.
It's his cuticles, I wish
I could stay so thin.
What?
Boy, this magazine kills me.
Look at this.
Help for your hips.
Cucumber poultice
you can make at home.
Huh, yeah right.
What? Huh?
I said, "cucumber poultice."
Can you believe it?
Uh, what? Uh, oh...
Gypsy,
turn this thing off.
- What? Oh, okay.
- Yeah.
Oh, man, my head itches.
Gee, I hope I don't get
a rash on my neck.
Oh, will you
look at the time?
I gotta get
to the store yet,
and then I gotta
grab the kids by three,
- because, you know,
wilbur's got--
- whoa.
Forget the kids, crow.
We got a visitor.
Cambot, let's check out
rocket number nine.
Hey, turn on
that viewscreen.
- It's gamera.
- By golly, it is gamera.
Oh great, the visit
of the century
- and me in rollers.
- Shh!
Hey, big turtle guy.
Hi boys, I was
just finishing up
some of my laundry here.
You know, great thing about
being a turtle is, uh,
you don't have
to separate your wash.
Because it's all green.
Anyway, I stopped in, uh--
can I borrow a, uh,
cling-free?
- You got one laying around?
- Uh, well, sure,
if you wouldn't mind
answering a couple of questions
about life as
a six-story turtle.
No, no-- no problem.
Go ahead.
Okay, well,
why do you go about
stomping on cities
and stuff?
Well, it's not my fault.
Listen,
I'm big-boned, right?
And let's face it.
City planners discriminate
against these
big-bone types, right?
The other day, I went into
a library turnstile.
Got stuck.
Bear grease, jaws of life.
Fire department came.
The whole mess.
And, uh, I was in a lot of pain,
let me tell you.
Of course, you'd know
about pain.
You've seen spalding gray.
- You know what I'm saying?
- Uh-huh.
Well, so what's the deal
with that boy kenny?
You guys seem
to be such chums.
Kenny, kenny kenny kenny.
Little, sweet kenny.
The deal with kenny is,
he's a good kid.
Good-hearted,
don't get me wrong.
But, uh, I'm using him.
You know,
'cause let's face it.
He softens up my image,
you know? Right?
- Kenny.
- Well, i--
well, look, I can
smash a huge city,
take out thousands
of people, right?
Say, a suburb of osaki.
Kill ten million.
And then, uh, you know,
with kenny at my side,
I look like jimmy stewart in
mr. Smith goes to washington.
It's great.
Let me tell you something
about that unconditional
love, children.
It feels really good.
- [Phone rings]
- Oh, excuse me.
Gotta take this.
Hello?
Godzilla,
how are you, buddy?
Yeah, yeah,
read the script, love it.
I got a title suggestion
for you.
See how this grabs you
by the po-po.
Uh, how about
gamera vs. Godzilla?
Yeah.
Yeah, all right.
Right. Right.
We-- yeah, no,
we can change it.
Call my agent.
Yeah, all right.
All right, bye.
Oh, listen, I gotta get going.
Got a few more things to do.
But, uh, it's been nice
talking to you,
and remember-- remember what
this turtle told you.
Keep your shell in the sun,
and always keep reaching
for the stars.
- Bye.
- If you see tibby,
tell her I said hello.
Huh. Neat.
Feel I kind of liked
that turtle.
Seems like such a nice guy.
Yeah, so noble. So proud.
So big.
Hey, do you think
I look fat?
- No, not at all.
- Oh, I think I do.
Professor murase,
a visitor for you.
Hey joel, you won't believe it,
really cool.
We just met gamera.
He's really cool.
He's a really neat guy.
It's kenny--
- we just met gamera--
- I heard.
- Oh yeah.
- Yeah, sure.
And you know snuffleupagus
too, right?
- He doesn't believe us.
- And then he suddenly vanished.
You see, he was always
talking about gamera.
- So I thought that maybe--
- kenny? Gamera?
Hmm. ♪ death to the world ♪
♪ I shall be quick
and I'll be... ♪
Yeah, okay, I got it.
Sure, okay.
- Uh, pepperoni,
extra cheese.
- Last boat's just arrived.
Right.
Okay, they'll
take care of it.
30 minutes?
Once a garden spot.
Now a playground of death.
[Servo hums]
And do you take
this man to be
your lawfully
wedded husband?
Let go of me!
- You're coming with me.
- Let go!
- Is that who I think it is?
- What's going on?
A stowaway, sir.
A little boy.
- A little boy?
- [All] Oh no.
- It's kenny!
- Kenny.
- Here he is, sir.
- D'oh.
I was worried about gamera.
[All] Wah-wah-waaaah.
Kenny, you're a friend
of gamera, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, very much so.
- Let's go.
- I am his keymaster.
- Well--
- tea-time.
Let's begin.
Dr. Hidaka,
are you sure it's possible
to bring gamera here?
Of course.
A typhoon's approaching.
It'll be before then.
Now, get away from me,
you old fruit.
Come in, please.
This is oshima.
You can start z-plan.
Ze plan iz started.
[Servo laughs]
Quickly, twist
the rubber band!
Get it on that little hook!
Now, turn the propeller!
Toy boat. Toy boat.
[All] Toy boat, toy boat.
- [All] Toy boat--
- toy plane?
Wait a minute.
- Okay--
- all right,
we're filling the bay
with brew!
[All] Whoo!
Nora, I have good news.
- I just got an order
for chicken littles.
- They found kenny.
- He's in oshima.
- Oh.
- And the good news?
- Thank god.
Thank god.
Now, let's see,
what could
I screw up big-time?
Yeah, that's it. Boats!
Everybody needs boats.
[Phone rings]
- Hello.
- Yes, hello?
Hidaka speaking.
Gamera wants $50,000 in cash
and a getaway...
[Servo mutters]
You can begin.
Yes, right now.
- You may give the order.
- Regular or crispy.
Stand by.
Take your positions.
[All]
Aah! Scatter! Everybody!
It's like
a jerry lewis platoon.
Like shootin' barrels
in a fish, officer.
Flame on.
Ooh.
Yay.
That's neat.
What, are they
watching tennis?
Oh, dear god.
They are watching tennis.
See?
[Gamera groans]
Hey, smoke on
the water, dude.
Fire in the sky.
- You did it.
- The plan's working.
- Neat.
- Dr. Hidaka, dr. Hidaka!
Gamera's moving! He's passing
right in front of us.
- Wonderful.
- Marvelous.
Gamera is heading this way.
- Yeah.
- Hello?
- All right.
Yes, everything's ready.
All right.
Everybody look!
Is it coming?
- Please be patient.
- Shut up.
- Hey, his binoculars fogged up.
- We bring you the latest news
regarding the typhoon.
The typhoon suddenly
changed its course
and is heading in
a northeastern direction.
If it continues
on its present course,
it will very shortly
hit the japanese mainland
causing untold devastation
and destruction.
Now, sticks
on the traffic jam.
- What shall we do?
- Ruuuun!
There is nothing we can do
but wait now.
Gamera! Gamera is coming!
Gamera is coming!
♪ Gamera's coming
gamera's coming ♪
♪ hey everybody,
Emperor kenny.
It's got a nice ring to it.
I will soon
be crowned king.
Gamera! Gamera!
Don't come!
Don't come here!
Kenny?
Kennarino! Kenster!
The ken-monster!
Hey.
- Gamera!
- Gamera, come on!
- Come on, you little--
- come on, that's it!
Heel time, boy, come on.
[Joel pats knee]
- Come on up.
- Alle, alle vi.
Talk about a banaca blast.
Oof.
Boy, hot breath.
That's it! That's it!
Yes, oh yes.
You know, he didn't
start the fire.
It was always burning
since the world was turning.
Thank you, uh, joel.
It's stopping.
Kenny!
Ken-ny!
Pineapple back.
We have failed.
There has to be another way.
Dr. Hidaka,
don't you think
it's about time
- we start using z-plan?
- [Servo mumbles]
- We mustn't.
- Why not?
We're saving it for
the next film!
We haven't enough fuel.
To attack now
would be pointless.
Darn.
Wait a minute.
Doctor!
Nurse.
H-- what is this,
frank burns?
Margaret, I love you!
I'm doing it for you!
Stop that! Stop that!
- Stop that man!
- Who is that madman?
But-- doctor, it's alex!
Let it burn! Let it burn!
Burn, baby, burn!
It's a disco inferno.
Let go. Catherine.
Alex, reporters aren't allowed
here. You know that.
Especially pyro reporters.
But I tagged along anyhow.
But not just for the story.
- I love you.
- I swear, I really came along
- only to help you.
- Oh.
I came by sea on
that tanker there.
I was worried about you.
But did you
start those fires?
- Yeah.
- I did it for you!
I started with a spark
from my heart.
Gamera is drawn to fire.
It will notice the fire
and then land here.
- Yes, yes, I see.
- That's right,
he'll kill us all,
- that's a great idea.
- It's a great idea.
Come on, give us a hand!
Give us a hand!
Aah! I like it!
Whoa. Burn everything!
- Woo-hoo!
- I scared myself,
I am evil.
Kenny!
And now gamera
in a scene from...
Here to eternity.
That's more like the length
of this movie.
[Servo chuckles]
Kenny, join me, and together
- we will rule the uni-- oh.
- Darth turtle?
- Different film.
- Keep them going.
Fire them all!
Hey, it's just like
a klan meeting.
Without the charm.
[Gamera roars]
I'm hysterical and wet!
Oh, great,
all they need now
is a plague of locusts,
you know?
Hey everybody,
catch the drops on your tongue.
Ready? Rock, lock...
Man, that poor
cross-country team.
They gotta go
through everything.
Doctor!
I've got it.
We'll move
the picnic inside.
Yeah.
There's no inside left.
Gamera!
You never loved me, kenny.
It's just the rocks
that you cared about!
It's turning around.
We failed again, I'm sorry.
You did everything
you could, doctor.
It's no use. Lousy rain.
[All] Shame. Shame.
Eternal shame.
Here's someone
that can help you.
[Gamera roars]
Now what?
Be afraid. Be very afraid...
Of kenny.
I'm only a sentinel
for kenny.
I get a lot of attention
because I'm big.
Look! Gamera's turning!
He's turning japanese.
I really think so.
I'll have what
the volcano's having.
[Gamera roars]
Gee, I don't know if
I should go for the people,
the volcano,
or wait for the pizza.
Hey, notice how the water
rolls off his back.
It's that turtle wax shell.
- Where's this at?
- End of the world.
Oh.
[Crow coughs]
Uh, you're flying with
a lawnmower handle.
- Permission to land.
- Request granted.
You can come in.
The volcano
stopped erupting.
- That was quick.
- Okay, thank you.
Hey, aaron spelling's house.
- There it is.
- --N't.
Ooh, I hope they don't crash
into the tower again.
Kenny, wake up, kenny.
Nora.
- Nora!
- Nora's theme.
I have to scold you.
Scold me later--
there's no time now.
- I'll enjoy it more.
- ...The z-plan!
Say.
- It's fantastic!
- So much to see,
- so much to do!
- Isn't it?
I can't believe that
we're really here.
- Kenny!
- Drink it all in, kenny.
Hurry, or you'll
get left behind!
Oh, they've walked into
a boston album cover.
Actually, it looks
like a mad fold-in.
[Bots] Yeah.
Matte painting, going up.
Oh, and matte painting
to the right.
Okay.
- Dr. Hidaka.
- Professor.
- Congratulations.
A complete success.
Thank you.
Oh, good, kenny's here.
We can start.
Stand by, please.
Well, give me
a phone to moscow
and a chocolate donut
for kenny.
We are ready to proceed
with z-plan.
Start the flames.
And the music!
Oh, uh,
the kennedy memorial?
Or greek theater, maybe.
Amphitheater.
Hey.
I know it's a trap,
but I can't resist.
I can't help myself.
I'm flawed.
- Let me through.
- Let him through!
It's kenny!
Come on.
[Gamera screams]
Now, watch me bust a move.
- [Servo beat-boxes]
- Nina peeples, look out.
- Look out.
- Watch the flame.
I am impressed.
There's a big piece
of cheese in the middle.
Uh...uh...
Are they gonna
flush him now?
Yep.
Aeschylus is stunning
as the great god tortoise.
Phase two. Now, phase two.
[All] Huh?
Hey, suddenly he's
a chewy nougat center.
We're putting gamera
in this soundproof booth.
Now we're gonna ask his wife
a few questions.
Now phase three.
Oh, they turned him into a giant
anti-perspirant roll-on.
Z-plan.
Beginning countdown.
- Ten...
- Three.
- Nine.
- 42.
- Eight.
- Ish kabibble.
- Seven.
- I forgot this number.
- Six.
- Pi.
- Googolplex.
- Five.
- 666.
- Four.
- Planck's constant.
- Three.
- [Servo mumbles]
- Two.
- Five, sir.
- Noonan.
- Noonan!
- Zero.
[Crow] Blugh.
Hey, joel,
remind you of anything?
- Yeah, reminds me of this.
- Aah!
- Hey, cut that out.
- Hey, joel.
♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
[Bots laugh]
You'll get sued for that.
I'm gonna sue you
for using that song.
[Bots] Bye!
- [Crow mutters]
- Goodbye, turtle friend.
I'm going to miss you.
Hey, he's got my keys!
Well, they launched merv
griffin's microphone into space.
- [All] Ooh.
- A special announcement.
The mars rocket
of the z-plan,
constructed with
the combined efforts
- of the world's superpowers,
- it's him again.
Was successfully launched
just now
with gamera
imprisoned inside.
We could not destroy
gamera on earth,
but the z-plan,
the last hope of mankind--
- destroyed him in space.
- Succeeded in sending gamera
- up to mars.
- Hmm.
It was made possible only
by the cooperation
of the member countries
of the united nations--
- and golan-globus.
- Proving once again
- that such great
achievements--
- I love you.
- Can only be realized
- keep coming back. It works.
- Thank you.
- Nice job. Good win.
Well, catherine,
I suggest you forget science
and instead really become
alex's inspiration.
You can't do both,
you're a woman.
- [They laugh]
- I itch.
Well, kenny,
gamera will be safe there.
- You happy?
- Yes, I'm glad
he wasn't killed.
I'm gonna be an astronaut
and ride in rockets.
And I'll see gamera
again, right?
Yeah, that's neat, but first,
you're grounded for life, kid.
Gamera! See you soon!
Hey kenny!
Get bent!
You hear that?
It's gamera's heart breaking.
He's heading for
that stain up there.
It's been there
the whole movie, too.
[Servo hums]
- Oh, now that was--
- gamera will be back
in the bells of st. mary!
Now, victory at sea!
[All] Or is it?
- Let's get out
of here, you guys.
- Let's beat it.
We have to--
we can't get out yet.
They won't let us out?
You mean there's more?
Well, there's a lot
of end here.
- Oh.
- Ah.
- Sandy frank, that's, uh...
- Didn't wanna miss that.
The source of all films.
Rock and roll. This is fun.
- [All sigh]
- Think they'll run
the credits again?
I don't know, I think they're
just gonna let us drift.
Hey, get me-- I'm a buoy!
Ding ding! Ding ding!
Whoa.
Kind of like lifeboat.
Yeah.
So.
- Oh.
- Let's get out of here.
- Ah, finally.
- Let's go.
- Neat crown.
- Jeepers.
You know, folks,
a quality cast
deserves a second look.
Cambot?
No japanese monster movie
would be complete
without this guy.
The japanese foster brooks,
our own tad hirokuma.
Watch for him
on the cbs special,
the fliar's roast:
Akira kurosawa.
Here's hideo fontaine,
established character actor,
who tragically died during the
making of this film.
Here's light rock's sensation
harry and carrie
carrie's gone on to be
an assistant/snake handler
FOR LAS VEGAS MAGICIAN,
SEñOR REY.
While harry has subsisted
on nothing
on nothing but
glade mist deodorant.
For the last three years
to prove his love
for coy carrie.
And there's so many more.
There's general curly
and eskimo pete.
The karnak knockoff.
Martha graham.
Colonel sanders-san.
Mister eddie's father.
Max, and trouser
the arctic pooch.
And let's not forget
kenny and gamera,
who will be appearing
in the broadway revival
of bob clampett's immortal
beany and cecil '91.
This is tom servo,
announcing.
Hey, you did a really
good job there, tom.
Good job, tom.
Yeah, you really put
that one to bed, servo.
Oh, well,
I really owe it all
to gary olan
and his radio clinic
for big-voiced men.
- Gary olan.
- Yeowch! Oh.
- Hey.
- That smarts.
- Okay, we got some letters.
To read from people
that've been sent up here
by the vietnamads.
And this one is--
comes with a photo.
Uh, it says,
"dear joel, tom servo,
- crow and gypsy"--
- yay!
"I first saw mst3k
about a year ago,
"and I've loved it
ever since.
"I showed it to my cousins,
and he loves it too.
Crow is my favorite,
especially his impersonations.
Do you know which one that one
is, the lloyd bridges he's got--
"by this time,
my lungs were,"
and you know how it goes.
- [Gypsy mumbles]
- Yeah, and, uh,
"please send
membership card information
and a photo of crow
with his autograph."
But this guy
went and made a model
of tom servo.
- Oh, look at that.
- Hey, neat.
Let me see that.
Say, that's pretty cool.
Looks like
a raster drawing of me.
Yeah, anyway, let's put that
up on still-store.
Looks like it's made
out of legos over there.
- [Gypsy] Lego.
- That's pretty neat.
That's it, sirs.
What'd you think?
And-- and thanks
for not sending
- such a bad movie
this time.
- Yeah.
What do you mean, thanks?
Oh, here. File this.
And give a joel a shock
to the shammies.
Only live to serve you,
my lord.
Ow! I got shocked
in the shammies...
♪♪
Bye.